hi everyone and welcome back to the
channel
2022. we're going to start this year
with a popular one ben and jerry's
chunky monkey
what is chunky monkey it's banana ice
cream with walnuts and chocolate tea
banana shapes chocolate tea not
chocolate banana shapes so if you want
to see how we make it
let's just get into it
first thing you're going to need to do
is take your bananas and if they're not
super ripe
like we couldn't wait any longer than we
had already to make this ice cream so
what you can do is cheat and put them in
the oven you can roast them for 10-15
minutes at
175 c whatever that is in fahrenheit and
once they're ready take them out the
oven let them cool down a little bit and
then get on to your ice cream base this
is a nice simple one actually it's a
little bit of a take on dana cree's base
but just a little bit different so put
all your ingredients apart from the
bananas in a pan and bring it up to
temperature you want to get this just
about to touch a boil and then leave it
there for a couple of minutes
once it's at that point you can then
turn the heat off and transfer it into a
container take your roasted bananas and
scoop out the flesh and put that in your
ice cream base you're gonna steep these
in there you are gonna take them out
before you churn by the way
[Music]
once all the bananas are in put it in
the fridge for a minimum of 24 hours
after that long 24 hours take the mix
out the fridge and then strain off the
banana so you don't you're gonna get any
leftovers you're not gonna crush them
you're not gonna put them in like loads
of other recipes tell you to do
this is the way to get true banana
flavored ice cream without the ice
crystals in it
then put it in your ice cream machine to
churn as you would do normally
[Music]
whilst your ice cream is churning you're
going to deal with your chocolate shapes
now we've got a silicon mold here that
has some banana shapes in there but as
i'm not particularly proud i'm going to
use all the fruit shapes that are also
available so we're going to have
chocolate bananas chocolate apples
chocolate pineapples chocolate cherries
you name it it's all going to go in here
melt your chocolate in a microwave
or over a bairi whatever suits you and
then fill up your silicone mold and put
it in the freezer
once they're hard shouldn't take long 10
minutes or so take it out the freezer
and pop them out and put them in a
container store that in the fridge until
you're ready to use it
finally the last part is just to chop up
some walnuts you can buy pre-chopped
walnuts or just buy hole however you
want to do it just chop them up to
about a centimeter in size any smaller
they'll disappear any bigger and they'll
just be a whole mouthful of water
again put it in a container put that
aside and we're going to use them in a
minute
now that you've got all your bits ready
your ice cream is churned take it out
and start loading up your tub put the
ice cream and then a layer of walnuts
and your chocolate shapes stir it in
nicely and fill that tub up until it's
completely full put it in the freezer
for a few hours
[Music]
here we go straight out the freezer look
at that dub junkie monkey
good one to start the year off i think
yeah and i've just noticed i've got a
purple halo above my head
anyway
so let's get some of this scoot up and
see what it looks like
there we go huge nice big round scoop of
banana ice cream walnuts and chocolate
shapes now i do not like banana ice
cream one of those flavors that i just
can't eat so
to try this one
we're gonna bring stacy my wife on so
say hello everybody
now i love my banana ice cream so i am
looking forward to tasting this
let's dig in
and when nick told me
that he was steeping the bananas and
then taking the flesh out
and not keeping the bananas in the ice
cream
i thought you wouldn't get any banana
flavor honestly
so that's never gonna work
that's really good
honestly the banana flavor comes across
so well it's so strong and it's not
overpowered
by
the walnuts and and the chocolate
actually has a big bit of chocolate
there i'm going to try this
chocolate adds a lovely dimension
oh lovely dark chocolate as well it cuts
through the banana but it doesn't
overpower it so i'm really surprised
that is really good ice cream
so we hope you enjoyed this video don't
forget to like and subscribe and we'll
see you and nick will see you in his
cookie monster lounge pants next week
[Music]
you